杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 接下来我们要做的就是把我们漂亮的骨头,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: The next thing we
wanna do is take our pretty bare bones,
无风格的主题，给它一些基础样式，并给它一些钩子。
unstyled theme and give it some
base styles, and give it some hook.
这样，使用主题的人就能够覆盖这些样式，并且
So that people who'll use the theme
are able to override those styles, and
让它看起来像他们的。
make it look like theirs.
所以让我们继续安装我们需要的东西。
So let's go ahead and
install what we need here.
那么我们就从盖茨比主题博士工作区开始吧。
So we'll start in
the gatsby-theme-docs workspace.
我们将添加，我们将添加主题-ui。
And we will add, we're gonna add theme-UI.
我们将添加 gatsby-plugin-theme-UI。
We're gonna add gatsby-plugin-theme-UI.
然后在引擎盖下面还有一些依赖性。
And then there are a couple
dependencies under the hood here.
第一个是情感 / 核心。
The first one is emotion/core.
然后我们还需要 mdx-js / react。
And then we also need mdx-js/react.
现在我们已经安装了 mdx-js / react。
Now we've already installed mdx-js/react.
我只是安装它作为这个过程的一部分，以展示中的完整依赖套件
I'm just installing it as part of this to
show the full suite of dependencies in
以防有人跳过。
case anybody skipped ahead.
但是再运行一次也没什么坏处。
But it doesn't hurt to run it again.
所以，一旦我们得到了这一点，我们可以进入我们的盖茨比配置和
So, once we've got this in,
we can go into our gatsby-config and
我们可以直接进入盖茨比主题，或者
we can just drop in gatsby-theme, or
不好意思，是 plugin-theme-ui。
gatsby-plugin, sorry, plugin-theme-ui.
所以我们可以看到在我们的包装,
And so we can see in our package.json,
我们有 gatsby-plugin-theme-UI，以及它的依赖项。
we've got the gatsby-plugin-theme-UI,
and its dependencies.
还有我们的 gatsby-config，我们有 gatsby-plugin-theme-UI。
And our gatsby-config,
we've got gatsby-plugin-theme-UI.
这样做的目的是将站点的输出包装在一个主题提供程序中，因此
And what this will do is it'll wrap the
output of the site in a theme provider, so
我们网站的不同部分可以访问这个主题。
that different parts of our site
are able to actually access that theme.
为了让这真正起作用，让我们进入并修改一些东西。
To make this actually work,
let's go in and modify a couple things.
所以我们要做的第一件事就是让我们的布局看起来不错。
So the first thing we wanna do is
let's get our layout to look nice.
首先，我希望能够使用主题 UI 快捷方式。
And I'm gonna do that by first, I wanna
be able to use the theme UI shortcuts.
它有一个道具，比如一个叫做 SX 的便利道具,
It has a prop,
like a convenience prop called SX,
这让我们可以访问主题 UI 道具和材料。
which lets us access
the theme UI props and stuff.
但是要做到这一点，我们必须改变杂注。
But to do that,
we have to change the pragma.
对于那些不熟悉它的人来说，这是一个杂注
A pragma for those of you who
aren't familiar with it is
React 神奇地识别 JSX 并将其转换为内容的方式。
the way that React magically recognizes
JSX and turns it into content.
这就是为什么当你需要的时候，你的反应必须在范围之内
It's why React has to be in Scope when you
创建一个组件，即使你实际上并没有引用 React import。
create a component even if you don't ever
actually reference the React import.
因此，如果我们更改了杂注，我们就不再需要 React 和
So if we change our pragma,
we no longer need React and
范围，因为我们提供了一个新的 create 元素函数
Scope because we're providing a new
create element function that will do
基本上和 React 一样，但是它增加了额外的功能。
basically all the same things that React
does, but it adds extra functionality.
在这种情况下，我们增加了对 SX 支持。
In this case we're adding support for
that SX prop.
为了做到这一点，我将把我们的 pragma 改为 JSX。
So to do that,
I'm going to change our pragma to JSX.
然后在这里，我要去
And then down here, I'm going
从 Beam UI 导入 JSX。
to import JSX from Beam UI.
然后因为我们不再需要反应,
And then because we don't
need React anymore,
我只是把它换成碎片。
I'm just gonna swap this
out to fragment only.
我们就像这样简化。
And we'll just simplify down like that.
我使用片段，这样我们就不会得到空的包装 div。
And I'm using fragments so
that we don't get like empty wrapper divs.
片段类似于编译，并没有成为实际的标记,
Fragment kind of compiles away and
doesn't become actual markup,
这使得我们的网站更加语义化,
which keeps our websites
a little more semantic,
如果你看的是源头，就更容易推理了。
a little bit easier to reason about
if you're looking at the source.
现在我们有了这个杂注,
So, now that we've got
this pragma in here,
我们可以开始添加一些风格。
what we can do is we can
start adding some styles.
所以我要补充的第一点就是
And so the first thing that I
wanna add is I'm just gonna add
这个 SX 道具我的头。
this SX prop to my header.
我想设置一下背景。
And I wanna set the background.
所以一开始有点棘手的主题之一是,
And so one of the things that's a little
tricky at first about theme-UI,
然后奇妙的是，它有捷径方法，所以
and then wonderful is that
it has shortcut methods so
你不需要输入很长的财产名称。
that you don't have to type out
really long property names.
所以我可以直接输入 bg，而不是输入背景。
So instead of typing out background,
I can just type bg.
我希望我的标题的背景是我的网站的主要颜色。
And I want the background of my header
to be the primary color on my site.
我们还没有定义这些颜色，所以不用担心。
And we haven't defined these colors yet,
so don't worry.
我们马上就会讲到这一点。
We'll get to that in a second.
我希望我的标题颜色是网站的背景颜色。
I want the color of my header to be
the background color of the site.
我希望字体家族是标题字体家族。
I want the font family to
be the heading font family.
我想把衬垫放好因为这是很常见的,
And I wanna set the padding,
and because it's a common one,
有一条捷径，我们可以设置填充物。
there's a shortcut,
we can set the padding.
我希望填充物是三个。
I want the padding to be three.
所以我可以设置，我们可以看到这里，它只是作为一个道具,
So I can set that and we can see here
that it's just on the header as a prop,
这是一个类似于主题-ui 样式的主题-ui 快捷方式。
and this is a theme-UI shortcut for
like theme-UI styles.
然后主要地，我还要添加一些东西。
Then on the main,
I'm gonna add a few things as well.
所以我想设置这一个是，我只想留下的空白和
So I want to set this one to be,
I only want the margin left and
右转为自动，使其中心在屏幕上。
right to be auto so
that it centers in the screen.
但是这也有一个捷径。
But there's a shortcut for that as well.
我们可以选择 x 或者左，右，然后设置为自动。
We can do margin x or left, right,
and I'm gonna set that to auto.
我要把 maxWidth 设置为650像素。
I'm gonna set the maxWidth to 650 pixels.
我要设置宽度为90，或者
I'm gonna set the width to 90, or
90 view port width units i think is what that’s short for。
90 view port width units I
think is what that's short for.
这样就可以防止它被小的侧面挤压
And that'll prevent it from getting
squished up against the sides on small
视图端口。
view ports.